So we are getting into the ECS Section,
but before talking about ECS we need to talk about Docker.
So Docker is something you may have heard before.
I'll try to simplify it.
You can make a 12 hour long course on Docker.
We'll try to make it short in four minutes.
So what is Docker?
Docker is a software development platform to deploy apps.
So the way we've been deploying applications from before
is to install them on Linux
and then they will work,
but with Docker, you will package your app
into something called a container
and that container is very special,
because it can be run on any operating system very easily.
The app, once in a container
will run the exact same way,
regardless of where they're run.
So it could be any machine,
no compatibility issues with predictable behavior,
less work, easier to maintain and deploy.
It will work with any programming language,
any operating system, any technology
and with Docker you can scale containers up and down
very quickly in a matter of seconds.
So that makes Docker
something that is extremely powerful nowadays
to deploy applications.
So if we talk about Docker on an EC2 Instance,
we would have, for example,
a Docker running Java code,
a Docker running NodeJS code,
a Docker running in My SQL Database,
a Docker running Java and so on
all onto the same EC2 Instance.
So the idea is that if we managed to package our application
in a Docker container,
then it will become very easy for us to run it
on an EC2 Instance.
So Docker images, you need to create them.
This is how your container will be run
and they can be stored
in something called Docker Repositories.
So there is a public Docker Repository called the Docker Hub
available at this address.
And you can find the base images for many technologies
or operating systems.
So for Ubuntu, which is a Linux Operating System,
or My SQL, this is a database technology,
NodeJS Java Programming Languages
or as we'll see in this section,
we can use Amazon ECR,
which is a private Docker Repository.
This is where you can store your private Docker images.
So this is more advanced,
but the question is, do you wanna use Docker
or virtual machine?
So Docker is sort of a visualization technology,
but not exactly.
So the resources are shared with a host.
That means that you can have many containers on one server.
So if we look at comparing EC2 and Docker,
this is all in the works.
So we have the infrastructure which is on AWS,
the Host Operating System,
then the Hypervisor
and this is stuff we don't have access to.
And then finally, when we get an EC2 Instance,
we have our application onto the Guest Operating System
and so if we want another EC2 Instance,
it will be created like this
and a third EC2 Instance, it will be credited like that.
So this works great
and this is what happens when we create EC2 Instances.
But in the case of Docker, we have the infrastructure,
the Host OS which is the EC2 Instance
and then the Docker Daemon.
And then as soon as the Docker Daemon is running,
we can have many containers running on to the Docker Daemon
and they're more light weights.
They don't package,
they don't come with a full operating system
and a virtual machine, all of them.
And so that makes Docker very versatile, very easy to scale
and very easy to run.
So this is just an overview of Docker.
You don't need to know what Docker is going into the exam,
but I wanted to give you that sweet little overview
in case you were curious
and in the next lecture,
we'll deal about how to do Docker on AWS
and that will be ECS.
So I will see you in the next lecture.