Now, let's talk about Amazon EKS.
So EKS is for Elastic Kubernetes Service,
and this allows you to launch and manage
Kubernetes cluster on AWS.
So what is Kubernetes?
Well, that's this blue logo right here,
and so Kubernetes is an open source system
that is used for the management, deployment,
and scaling of containerized applications,
usually, managed by Docker containers,
but could be other types of containers as well.
So these containers and these pods
can be hosted on either EC2 instances or using Fargate,
if you want it to be fully serverless.
So if you use an EKS cluster,
a Kubernetes cluster managed by EKS,
then you're going to have, for example, EKS nodes,
for example, in this case, there are EC2 instances.
And so, whenever you launch a Docker container
on your Kubernetes cluster,
automatically, pods are going to be launched
onto your EC2 instances.
So why would you use Kubernetes on Amazon EKS?
Well, launching Kubernetes is quite hard,
and so using a managed service
to manage your Kubernetes cluster is a great idea,
hence the idea behind Amazon EKS.
And why should you use Kubernetes?
Well, if you are using multiple clouds
or even on-premises infrastructure,
then Kubernetes can run everywhere,
and so therefore, this is cloud agnostic,
and therefore, learning Kubernetes can allow you
to learn how to launch containers anywhere would be on AWS,
but also Azure or GCP or anywhere else, and that's the idea.
From an exam perspective,
you will just see the word Kubernetes,
and you have to think about Amazon EKS.
All right, that's it, I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.