So now, I want to formally introduce
the Serverless Section to you.
So what is severless?
Severless is a catchy word but it is a new paradigm
in which the developers don't manage the servers anymore.
They just do what they do best,
they just deploy the codes or they deploy functions.
So initially, serverless was pioneered
as a Function as a Service with AWS Lambda,
and that means that you just deploy your code
and each function will be run independently
by the Lambda service, but nowadays,
anything that's serverless
is mostly mentioned as something that is managed
and that does include servers managed by the user
so that includes serverless databases,
messaging, storage, et cetera.
So serverless does not mean that there are no servers.
There are, of course, servers behind the scenes.
Otherwise, services would not work,
but it just means that as an end user,
you don't manage, provision, or even see the servers.
So in this course,
we have been using some serverless services
from the beginning.
So Amazon S3 was one of them
because we used it as a storage layer,
but we didn't manage any servers at all, okay?
Amazon S3 can scale infinitely, there was no servers,
it was just uploaded file, and that was it.
DynamoDB was another one.
So in DynamoDB, we just went ahead, we created a table,
but we didn't provision a server for that table,
and that server was, that table could auto scale
based on the load it was receiving.
So that makes it another serverless service.
Fargate is another one
so Fargate was to run Docker containers,
and as I said with ECS, you create EC2 instances
to run the Docker containers
so that would not be serverless, but with Fargate,
you just send the Docker containers
and Fargate will automatically find a way for it to be run
so that makes it another serverless service,
and in this section, we're going to see Lambda,
which was the pioneer of serverless services.
So Lambda allows you to run functions in the cloud.
So this is it for the quick intro to serverless,
I will see you in the next lecture to talk about Lambda.