Now let's talk about a quick service
called the Amazon API Gateway.
So this comes from the use case from an exam perspective
of you wanting to build a server less HTTP API.
So in this example, we have server less technologies
so we're using Lambda,
and we're Reading, Creating, Updating and Deleting data
from DynamoDB,
which are both server less technologies
but we want external clients to be able to access our Lambda
function.
But a Lambda function is not exposed as an API right away.
For this we need to expose it
through an API Gateway
which is going to provide the client with the rest HTTP API
to connect directly to your website.
And so, as we can see the client
will talk to the API Gateway.
The API gateway will proxy the request
to your lender functions
which will execute the transformations on your data.
And so API Gateway is used
as a fully managed service
that is going to allow developers
to easily create, publish, maintain,
monitor, and secure APIs in the cloud.
It is a server less technology,
and it is fully scalable.
It supports RESTful APIs,
and also WebSocket APIs for real time streaming of data.
It supports also security, user authentication,
API throttling, API keys, monitoring, and so on.
So when you see going to exam
which creates a server less API
you need to think about API Gateway and Lambda.
That's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.