Amazon Lightsail is a bit of an oddball in AWS
because it is kind of a stand-alone service.
So with Lightsail,
you can get virtual servers,
storage,
databases
and networking in one place.
It gives you low and predictable pricing.
And so the reason people use Amazon Lightsail
is that it is a much simpler alternative
to using services
that we've been learning
such as EC2 RDS, ELB, EBS, Route53 and so on.
So Lightsail really the intent of it from AWS
is for people that have little cloud experience
and don't want to learn
how the services work intricately,
for example,
how their networking works,
how the storage works,
the server works etc.
This is not something you would use
your learning how AWS works properly
but if you're someone with little
to no cloud experience
then Lightsail maybe a service for you.
From Lightsail you can also set up some monitoring
and notifications for your Lightsail resources
and so use cases for Lightsail would be
for example,
if you want to deploy a very simple web application
if you have LAMP Stack, Nginx, MEAN, Node.js
there's templates for that on Lightsail
or if you have a very simple website,
for example,
if you have a WordPress and Magento,
Plesk, Joomla
all these kind of things can be deployed
very easily on Lightsail.
Finally, Lightsail is also great
if you have development and test environments in AWS.
There is a concept of high availability in Lightsail
but there's no auto-scaling
and there really are limited AWS integrations.
So to summarize,
Lightsail really is something
that you wouldn't use today on your own
but from an exam perspective
if you see someone
that has no cloud experience
and need to get started quickly
with a low and predictable pricing
without configuring things much
that will be Lightsail,
otherwise Lightsail will almost
always be a wrong answer.
So I hope that was helpful
and I will see you in the next lecture.