Okay, so let's do a summary of all
these new compute services we've just learned about.
And the first thing is that we learned about Docker,
which is a technology,
a container technology that allows you to run applications.
And we've seen how to run Docker on AWS.
The first way is to use ECS.
And this is going to allow you to run your Docker containers
on EC2 instances, but you have to provision
these instances in advance.
For Fargate, it is the exact same way
but this time we run the Docker containers
without provisioning the infrastructure,
it is transparent to us.
And then next Fargate, a serverless offering
because we don't manage any EC2 instances
to run these Docker containers.
These Docker containers can be stored on the AWS using ECR,
which has a Private Docker Images Repository.
And we've also seen about the batch service.
Batch allows you to run batch jobs on AWS
across a set of managed EC2 instances.
And actually, the batch service actually runs
on top of the ECS service.
We've finally seen about a new type of service
to run predictable and low pricing simple applications
and database techs, which is LightSail,
which is most likely going to be a distractor at the exam
but we've done a hands-on, and now we knew what to expect
and how the service works.
So now let's talk about Lambda.
Lambda is going to be a serverless service
which is going to give you
a capability of function as a service,
and it's going to have seamless scaling.
So from one invocation
to thousands of invocation per second,
and it's fully reactive.
You have two components for building of Lambda.
You have by the time run,
times the amount of memory provisions
for the Lambda function.
And also by the number of times your Lambda function
has been invoked.
In terms of language supports,
it supports many different kinds of programming languages.
And even though it supports container images
and then need to implement a specific runtime API.
And so I like to say that Lambda does not support
arbitrary Docker images,
for this you would use ECS and Fargate,
but if your Docker image does implement
the Lambda container Runtime API,
then you can run Docker images on Lambda,
but this is not the standard again.
The invocation time is up to 15 minutes
and the use cases for Lambda is to create funnels
for images uploaded onto Amazon history, for example,
or to run a serverless Cron job.
Finally, if we wanted to expose our Lambda functions
as APIs, we would use another serverless service
called the API Gateway,
that would allow us to expose our functions as HTTP APIs,
but also give us capabilities around security, front Ling,
API keys, and so on.
So that's it for this section, I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next section.