Okay, so now new have an application
that can be load balanced through a load balancer,
but how do we create, automatically
these servers in the back end.
For this we can use an auto scaling group.
So why?
Well in real life you're load on the websites
can change over time.
So for example, say your users are doing shopping,
they're most likely doing shopping during the day
and not at night.
So you expect more load during the day
and less load during the night.
So in the cloud we know we can create
and get rid of servers very quickly
and so the goal of an auto scaling group is to scale out.
That means add EC2 instances to match an increased load
or scale in, that means remove EC2 instances
to match a decreased load.
With this we can ensure that we have,
also as well, a minimum,
and a maximum number of machines
running at any point of time
and once the auto scaling group does create,
or remove EC2 instances we can make sure
that these instances will be registered,
or de registered into our load balancer.
So these two things work hand in hand.
Finally, in case one of our servers becomes unhealthy,
maybe there's an application bug,
then the auto scaling group can detect it
and say, yeah, you know what,
I don't need an unhealthy instance.
I'm going to de register it.
I'm going to terminate it
and replace it by a new healthy one.
So with an auto scaling group we get a lot of benefits
and another benefit we get,
is that we have huge cost savings,
because we are only running all the time
at the optimal capacity
and that is one of
the guiding principle of the cloud, elasticity.
So if we look at our autos scaling group in AWS.
This is it.
We have a minimum size, maybe it's one EC2 instance.
Then there is a setting called desired capacity,
which is also usually the actual size
of your auto scaling group
and then finally,
you can define a maximum size of you auto scaling group
and automatically your ASG, auto scaling group,
can scale out as needed
or scale in as needed by adding EC2 instances over time
and it work hand in hand with a load balancer.
So that means that if we have our auto scaling group,
for example, with one EC2 instance,
web traffic can be coming in through our load balancer,
which will be redirecting the traffic
directly into your EC2 instance
and as our auto scaling group scales out
by adding EC2 instances,
the load balancer will have them registered
and will send traffic to them as well.
So as we add on more and EC2 instances,
the load balancer distributes more
and more of the traffic,
all the way to the maximum size of your auto scaling group
if it scales all that point.
So that's it for this lecture.
In the next lecture
we will be reproducing that very same set up
with an auto scaling group, multiple EC2 instance,
and a load balancer.
So I hope that was helpful
and I will see you in the next lecture.