Okay, so we've seen how Auto Scaling Groups works
but let's have a look at the different Scaling Strategy
for your Auto Scaling Groups.
So the first one is to do Manual Scaling.
Which is when we update the size
of a Auto Scaling Group manually.
And this is when for example,
we changed the capacity from one to two,
or back from two to one.
Then we can define some Scaling Strategies such as
Dynamic Scaling to respond
to changing demands automatically.
So we have different type
of scaling policies within Dynamic Scaling,
we have the Simple and the Step Scaling
which is the idea is
that whenever a CloudWatch alarm is triggered for example,
you say whenever the average CPU utilization
of all my EC2 instance goes over 70% for five minutes,
then add two units to capacity to my ASG.
Or when another alarm for example,
say whenever the CPU utilization is less
than 30% for 10 minutes.
Then remove one unit of capacity in my ASG.
This would be Simple or Step Scaling
because we define the trigger,
and then we define how many units we add or remove.
Then we have Target Tracking Scaling,
which is a very easy way of defining a scaling policy.
The example is to say,
hey I want the average CPU utilization
of all the EC2 instances in my ASG
to stay at around 40% on average
and then the ASG will scale automatically
to make sure that you stay around that target of 40%.
And we have also Scheduled Scaling.
So this is when we know
that changes are going to happen ahead of time.
So we anticipate a scaling based on known users pattern.
And for example we're saying,
hey we know that's on Friday at 5:00 PM.
People are going to do sports betting maybe who knows,
before the soccer game,
and so please increase the minimum capacity
to 10 EC2 instances in my ASG
at 5pm on Friday.
This could be a Scheduled Scaling
and there's one last type of scaling.
that is definitely appearing on the exam
which is called Predictive Scaling.
So this one uses Machine Learning
to predict future traffic ahead of time
so there's some algorithms,
they will look at the past traffic patterns,
and it will forecast what will happen
to traffic based on the past patterns.
And so the idea is that
it's called predictive because we predict
what the load will be over time,
and maybe the load is just on a daily basis
it peaks for three hours.
So this is the kind of things that
Predictive Scaling will pick up, okay.
And it will automatically provision
the right number of EC2 instances
in advance to match that predicted period.
So this is what the graphs you see on the right hand side.
This is very helpful
when you have time-based patterns
and you just want to have an easy,
without any intervention type of scaling
trust strategies
that is powered by Machine Learning,
then that would be Predictive Scaling.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And remember the strategies.
I will see you in the next lecture.