Okay, so let's summarize the section
on the ELB and the ASG.
So first, we discussed the concept of high availability.
Scalability would be vertical and horizontal,
elasticity and agility in the Cloud.
It is very important for you to understand
to which concept corresponds to which features.
For example, high availability
means that you are having your applications
across multiple availability zone.
Vertical scaling means that you're increasing the size
of an instance.
And horizontal scaling,
is that you are increasing the number of instances.
Elasticity is the ability to scale up and down
based on demand.
And agility is a concept of the Cloud that is going
to be able to make you work faster,
because you can create and delete resources
very, very quickly.
Now, our load balancers, or ELB,
are allowing us to distribute traffic
across backend EC2 instances, and they can be spread out
across multiple availability zones.
We support health checks to make sure
that the backend EC2 instances are indeed healthy.
And we have four kinds of load bouncers.
The classic one is old and retired.
We have the application balancer for HTTP type of workload
at the layer seven.
Network load balancer for very high performance
and TCP level load balancing, layer four.
And finally, the gateway load balancer, layer three,
to route the network itself, and make it go by, for example,
through some virtual appliances.
We have auto scaling groups that allow us
to implement elasticity for our application,
therefore spreading our load across multiple AZ
and scaling accordingly.
So we scale these EC2 instances
based on the demand on your system,
and we can replace unhealthy instances.
There's a tight integration between the ASG and the ELB.
So this is why they are a great combination,
and together, we achieve high availability, scalability,
elasticity, and agility in the Cloud.
All right, that's it.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.