So now let's talk about Amazon S3-Security.
The first part is User-Based.
So as a user you can have IAM policies that you
and this IAM policy is going to authorize
which API calls should be allowed for a specific IAM user.
You can also have Resource-Based Security.
So this is new.
We can use what's called S3 Bucket policies
and there are bucket wide rules
that you can assign directly from the S3 console.
And this will allow, for example, a specific user to come in
or allow a user from another account,
this is called cross-account
to access your S3 Buckets.
This is also how we'll make our S3 Buckets public
as I will show you in a minute.
Next, you have the Object Access Control List or ACL,
they're finer grain security and they can be disabled.
And if you need to go
at the Bucket level, you can have Buckets ACL
which is way less common also can be disabled.
And the most common way now to do security
on an Amazon S3 Bucket is to use Bucket policies.
So in which situation can an IAM principle
can access an S3 object?
Well, if the IAM permissions allow it
or if the resource policies allows it
and that there is no explicit deny in the action,
then the IAM principle can access the S3 object
on the specified API call.
So we'll have a look at these use cases in a minute.
Finally, another way to do security on Amazon S3
is to encrypt the objects using encryption keys.
So what does S3 Bucket policy actually look like?
Because this is the focus of S3-Security for us.
So they are JSON based policies and they look like this.
So this is JSON documents and it's quite easy to read.
So the first thing is that you have a resource block
and the resource tells the policy
what buckets and object this policy applies on.
And in here we can see that this applies to every object
within the example Bucket,
this is what the star is for.
Next we have the effect.
So Allow or Deny, and what do we Allow or Deny?
Well, we Deny actions.
So we have a set of APIs we can either Allow or Deny
and in this example, the action we Allow is GetObject.
So this allows anyone thanks to the principle,
the principle presents the account or the user
to apply the policy to so principle is star.
So, here we allow anyone with a star to GetObject,
so to retrieve an object from my example Bucket
with a start, that means any object within it.
So therefore this S3 Bucket, is setting public reads
on all objects inside my Buckets.
So we can use an S3 Bucket policy
to grant public access to the Bucket
as the one shown on the right hand side
or to force objects to be encrypted at upload
or to grant access to another account.
So let's have a look at the situation.
So here is a Bucket Policy for Public Access.
So we have a user, it's on the worldwide web
it's a website visitor
and he wants to access files within our S3 Buckets.
So we'll attach an S3 Bucket policy
that allows public access.
This is the one you've seen in the previous slide.
And once this Bucket policy is attached to the S3 Bucket
then we can access any objects within it.
That's what we'll see in the hands-on.
But another way to do it
is that if you have a user within your account,
so it's an IAM user
and that user wants to access Amazon S3,
then we can assign IAM permissions
to that user through a policy.
And therefore because the policy allows access
to the S3 Buckets
then the user can access our S3 Buckets right now.
If we have an EC2 instance and want to give access
from the EC2 instance into the S3 Buckets,
we've seen that IAM users are not appropriate.
We need to use IAM roles instead.
So we create an EC2 instance role
with the correct IAM permissions
and that EC2 instance will be able to access
the Amazon S3 Buckets.
More advanced,
if we want to allow Cross-Account Access,
then we must use the Bucket Policy.
So we have an IAM user in another AWS account
and we create an S3 Bucket policy
that allows Cross-Account Access for that specific IAM user
and therefore the IAM user will be able to make API calls
into our S3 Buckets.
Other security settings you need to know about
is that there is the Bucket settings
for Block Public Access.
So this is what we set to own when we created the Buckets
and these settings were invented by AWS
as a extra layer of security to prevent company data leaks.
So even though you would set an S3 Bucket policy
that would make it public,
if these settings are enabled,
the Bucket will never be public.
So this is to prevent data leaks.
So if you know that your Bucket should never be public,
then leave these settings on
and you have this level of security
against people who would set the wrong S3 Bucket policy.
And if you know that none
of your S3 Buckets ever should be public,
then you can set this at the account level.
Okay, so that's it for S3-Security.
Now let's go in the hands-on to practice.