So let's go ahead and make a bucket policy
so that we can access this coffee file from the public URL.
So to do so, let's go under the Permission tabs.
And the first thing we have to do is
to allow public access from the bucket setting,
because right now everything is blocked.
So we edit this and we're going to untick this,
and, therefore, we will allow public access.
But again, this is something you would disable
only, and only if, you know you want
to set a public bucket policy.
So this is dangerous action.
So we say yes, because, of course, if you set real data
of your company on an S3 bucket and you make this public,
you have data leaks and that can never be good.
So now, under Permissions overview,
the access that objects can be public.
So that's the first step.
Next, we scroll down and we look at Bucket policy.
So currently we have none and we wanna create one
so that we make our entire bucket public.
So the first thing you can do is look
at the policies example, and this is the documentation,
and it will show you a lot
of use cases on the right hand side
that will show you what's the appropriate
and corresponding bucket policy.
But for us, we're going to use the policy generator.
So here's the AWS Policy Generator,
and we're going to create an S3 Bucket Policy.
So let's select the right type.
We'll allow, and then the principal is going to be a star
because we want to allow anyone
on the Amazon S3 service to perform,
and because we will read objects on our bucket,
we want to perform a getObject.
So here it is.
We want to allow getObjects.
And the Amazon Resource Name must be the bucket name
with a slash, and then with a star.
So let's have a look first.
So back into our S3 buckets, we have the bucket arn here,
the Amazon resource name here.
So we copy it, we paste it into the Amazon Resource Name,
and this is not over.
We add a slash and then we add a star.
And the reason why we do this is that this action,
the getObject action right here,
applies to objects within your buckets,
and, therefore, objects within your bucket
are after a slash and there are stars
to represent these objects.
So let's add these statements
and then let's generate this policy.
And this policy is what we copy into here,
and this is a public S3 policy.
So that means that getObjects are allowed from anyone
on any objects of this bucket.
Okay, that's good.
So let's save these changes.
And there is a space here, so let's remove this.
Perfect.
Save these changes.
Now that works.
So we can see that our bucket policy
has properly been applied.
So, now, let's go into our object, coffee.jpg,
and let's find the object URL, right here.
We copy it and we enter it.
And as you can see now, my coffee image is fully visible
and it is public as well as any other objects
in my Amazon S3 buckets.
So that's it for this lecture.
We've seen bucket policies, we've seen the policy generator,
and we've seen that now our image is public.
So I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.