So now let's talk about how Amazon S3
can be used to create aesthetic websites.
So S3 can host static websites
and have them accessible on the internet
and the website URL will be depending
on the AWS region where you create this,
either this or that.
And they look very, very similar as you can tell.
But the only difference is that here, you have a dash
and here, you have a dot.
It doesn't really matter for you to remember this
but just so you know, here it is.
So we have an extra bucket
and it will contain files, maybe HTML files, maybe images
and then we're going to enable this to be compatible
with hosting a website.
So this is what it will look like with the corresponding URL
and then the user will access our S3 buckets.
But this will not work
if we don't have public reads enabled on our S3 buckets.
And this is why in the first place,
in the last lecture we learned about S3 bucket policies.
So if you have a 403 forbidden error
after enabling your S3 bucket for reads,
then that means that your bucket is not public.
Therefore, you must attach an S3 bucket policy
that allows it to be public.
So that's it for this short lecture,
now let's go into the hands on to practice this.