Okay, so let's enable our bucket
to be a website.
But first, I'm going to upload one more file here,
I'm going to upload my beach.jpg file into our buckets.
Okay, this is done, so we have two files into our buckets,
and let's go into Properties, scroll down,
and all the way down
you will find the static website hosting.
So click on Edit,
and here we will enable static website hosting.
We want to host a static website
and we need to specify an index document.
So I will say, index.html
and we will have to upload that file.
This is the default or homepage of the websites.
As you can see here, we also have a little warning sign
saying, hey, by the way
if you want to enable this as a website endpoint
you must make all your content publicly readable.
And we've done this in the previous lecture, so that's good.
Okay, so let's go and save this.
So this is saved, and go back into our objects.
And the one thing that's missing here
is that index, that HTML file.
So let's go to upload this,
we Add files and then I will click on index.html
and then upload, close it.
It's created, so now back into Properties,
let's scroll all the way down,
and you see now that's under static website hosting,
we have a bucket website endpoint.
So I copy this URL, paste it,
and I get, I love coffee.
Hello world!
And my coffee.jpg file.
So this working, so this is my index at HTML file,
and if I right click on this and open this image in new tab,
we have the public URL of our coffee.jpg.
So this is working,
and by the way if you wanted to change the coffee for beach,
well under beach.jpg we can see as well
this beach image right here.
So that means that everything is working,
our S3 bucket is enabled for static website hosting,
and thanks to the S3 bucket policy being public,
we can see all these files.
So we're good to go, I hope you like this lecture
and I will see you in the next lecture.