So, now let's talk about versioning
in Amazon S3.
Because we've seen how to create a website,
but it would be nice to be able to update it in a safe way.
So, you can version your files in Amazon S3,
and this is a setting you have to enable
at the bucket level.
So, we have my bucket and it's enabled with versioning.
So, whenever a user uploads a file,
it's going to create a version of that file
at the selected key.
And then should we re-upload the same key,
should we overwrite that file,
then instead it's going to create a version two,
and then a version three, and so on.
So, therefore, it is best practice to version your buckets.
Why?
Well, the first thing is that it protects
against unintended deletes.
So, for example, if you delete a file version,
actually you just add a delete marker
and therefore you can restore versions
that were previously there instead.
You can also easily roll back to a previous version.
So, if you want to go back to what happened two days ago,
you can take a file and roll it back.
So, there are some notes you need to be aware of.
First of all, that any file that is not versioned
prior to enabling versioning will have the version null.
And also that if you suspend versioning,
it does not delete the previous version,
so, it's a safe operation.
Okay, so now let's go into the console
and have a look at how we can use versioning.