So now let's play with S3 versioning.
And so first you need to go into the properties
and then we have a bucket versioning setting.
We're going to edit this and we're going to enable it.
And this is to enable bucket versioning.
And therefore any files we override now
is just going to add versions into our buckets.
So this is good.
Let's go into our objects
and say we want to update our website.
So let's go back, find the website URL.
It is right here.
Okay, so we have "I love coffee"
but let's say we want to write, "I really love coffee"
so therefore let's go back into here, our file.
And I'm going to edit it
and say I really love coffee.
I've saved it.
And now I upload this file again.
So I'm going to add a file and it will be my index.html.
And now we have updated content in that file.
So if I upload it.
It's successful.
So now it's been overwritten.
If I go into my first webpage and refresh this,
I get "I REALLY love coffee."
But what did happen in the back?
Well, if we go here
and we have here this toggle "Show versions"
we're going to show the actual version ID with the files.
And so we can notice a few things.
Number one, the files that we had uploaded before
such as the beach.jpg and the coffee.jpg
have a null version id.
That's because they were uploaded
before we had enabled versioning.
But this file index.html as you can see has two versions.
One has version ID null, which is the file we had uploaded
before enabling versioning.
But the file we uploaded just right now has a version ID.
And therefore, by updating this file
and uploading it into our S3 bucket,
we have created a new version ID.
So this is something you can only see if you
enable this toggle.
So now thanks to versioning
what we can do is we can actually roll-back our page.
So we have, "I REALLY love coffee"
but we wanna go back to "I love coffee."
So how do we do this while we click on
this specific version ID
Okay, so make sure that "Show versions" is enabled
and then we're going to delete.
And here we have to delete a specific version ID
of our object.
And therefore when we delete a specific version ID
of our object, it's called a permanent delete.
So it's a destructive operation, it cannot be undone.
And so if we're sure, we type permanently delete
in this text box and click on delete objects.
And now if you go back, as we can see,
we are back with the previous date of our bucket.
And therefore if I refresh this page,
I just get "I love coffee."
But what if we disable "Show versions"?
So now we just have our objects
and I'm going to take this coffee.jpg file,
and I will delete it itself.
So this time we don't actually delete
the underlying version ID,
we delete by adding a delete marker.
And so it doesn't actually delete the underlying object
as we'll see.
Let's just type delete this time.
It's not permanently delete, it's just delete
and we delete the object.
Perfect.
So now if we have a look at it from within our bucket,
it looks like the coffee.jpg file is done.
But if we click on "Show versions"
we see that we have a delete marker on our coffee.jpg file
with this version ID.
And the real, the previous, at least, coffee.jpg file
is still in our buckets
but it's being overwritten at least right now
from a version perspective by a delete marker.
So back into our webpage, if I refresh this page
and I refresh it by forcing a refresh,
by doing a Command + Shift + R to force a refresh
then we see that the image is not available.
So how do we get back this image?
And if I just try to, for example,
open this image in the new tab, it doesn't work.
I get a "404 Not Found."
So instead to get back the previous objects
I can click on this delete marker
and I'm going to delete the delete marker.
So I will permanently delete this delete marker.
And the effect of that is that it will restore
the previous version of my object
which is this one from before.
So back into my webpage, if I refresh it now
we can see that the coffee.jpg file is there.
So you can play around with versioning
you can add as many file version as you want.
You can start deleting them and view what happens.
But I hope you like this lecture
and I will see you in the next lecture.