Now let's talk about Amazon S3 Replication,
and there are two flavors of it.
So CRR is for cross-region replication
and SRR is for same-region replication.
The idea is that we have an S3 Bucket in one region
and a target S3 Bucket in another region,
and we want to set up asynchronous replication
between these two buckets.
So, to do so, we first must enable Versioning
in the source and the destination buckets.
And if we do CRR, so cross-region replication,
the two regions must be different.
If we do SRR, the two regions are the same.
Now, it's possible for you to have these buckets
in different AWS accounts
and copying happens asynchronously.
So the replication mechanism happens behind the scenes,
in the background.
And to make replication work,
you must give proper IAM permissions
to the S3 service so that it has the permission
to read and write from specified buckets.
So the use cases for replication are manyfold.
The first one is that if you use cross-region replication,
this can be helpful for compliance
or for providing lower latency access to your data
because it's in another region,
or to replicate data across accounts.
For SRR, or same-region replication,
this can be very helpful to aggregate logs
across multiple S3 Buckets
or to perform a live replication
between a production and test accounts,
so, you have your own test environment.
Okay, so that's it about replication.
I will see you in the next lecture for some practice.