So let's practice replication
on Amazon S3.
For this, we're going to create a new bucket.
I'll call it S3 Stephane bucket origin V2,
and I will set it in one region that I want,
for example, EU west one.
This will be my origin buckets
and then data will be replicated
from this bucket to another bucket.
So the thing I need to do of course,
is to enable versioning
because replication only works
if versioning is enabled.
So I will create this bucket,
and then open this bucket in a new tab
and I will create a second bucket
and this will be my target bucket.
So I will do S3 Stephane bucket replica V2.
And this time, the region can be either the same,
for example, if you wanted to do same region replication
or something completely different,
for example if you wanted the US,
you could do US east one
to replicate from Europe to the US.
Okay, so let's scroll down
and let's again, enable bucket versioning
on the target buckets.
And we're good to go.
So now we have our primary buckets
and our secondary buckets.
What I'm going to do is that in the origin bucket,
I'm going to upload a file
so I will add a file of my beach,
for example, beach.jpeg.
Okay, this is done and we can close this.
So now this has one file,
but of course, this does not get replicated yet
because we haven't set up replication yet
so let's go ahead and do this.
So on the origin bucket,
what I need to do is to go under management,
scroll down and there are replication rules,
currently, zero.
So let's go ahead and create our first replication rule.
So I'll call this one demo replication rule.
Okay, perfect.
We'll set it as enabled.
For the source bucket,
we'll leave it as is
and in terms of rule scope,
we'll apply it to all objects in the buckets.
Now for the destination,
we can specify a bucket in this account
or in other accounts,
and we'll choose one in this account
and the bucket name is my target bucket.
So I need to actually enter the name.
So I'll take this bucket right here, copy and paste it.
Okay, and as you can see,
the destination region was identified
as being US east one,
so therefore, this is a cross region replication.
Okay, now for IAM role,
we need to actually go
and create a new role for this.
So there's the option.
And then we can have a look at some settings,
but for now, it doesn't really matter for us.
Let's just save this.
So we get a prompt right here,
which says, do you want to replicate existing objects?
So it turns out that when you do enable replication,
it will only replicate objects
from the moment you set it,
so for newer uploads.
So if you wanted to replicate the previous objects
from the source of the destination bucket,
you could use something called a batch operation,
an S3 batch operation to do so
and you would need to say yes, replicate existing objects,
but this is separate from the replication feature itself.
Therefore, I'm going to say no,
do not replicate existing objects
and we're good to go.
So now let's have a look.
So we have this management
with a replication rule that is ready.
And now what I'm going to do is check in my replica bucket.
Of course, if I refresh now,
we see that the objects haven't been replicated.
So I'm going to do is now upload a new file,
for example, upload the coffee.jpeg file,
upload it.
We're done.
So here is the coffee.jpeg file.
Let's show the version.
So this is coffee.jpeg and the version is GBK.
Okay, perfect.
Now, if we go in my target bucket and refresh this,
it's gonna take maybe five seconds.
And this took about 10 seconds on the first replication,
but we can see that my coffee.jpeg
has been added into my replica bucket.
And if I show the versions,
we can see the version ID
of my coffee.jpeg is the exact same of the origin bucket.
So the versions IDs are replicated, which is great.
And if I wanted to port the beach.jpeg,
I would need to upload a new version of that file,
so let's upload beach.jpeg again.
Now this has been uploaded.
We can look at the version.
So there is a new version right here
of DK2, of my beach.jpeg file.
And now if I go here and refresh,
and this took a bit of time, but as you can see,
you can find the DK2 version of that file.
So that's it for S3 bucket replication.
I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.