Okay, so let's discuss
different storage classes we have for Amazon S three.
The first one is Amazon S three Standard-General Purpose.
Then we have Amazon S three-Infrequent Access.
Then we have Amazon S three One Zone-Infrequent Access.
Then we have Glacier Instant Retrieval,
Glacier Flexible Retrieval, Glacier Deep Archive,
and then finally, the Amazon S three Intelligent Tiering.
So we'll learn about all these classes in depth
in this lecture, but you have to know them for the exam.
Then when you create an object in Amazon S three,
you can choose its class,
you can also modify its storage class manually,
or as we'll see as well,
you can use Amazon S3 Lifecycle configurations
to move objects automatically
between all these storage classes.
So first, before we go into the classes,
let's define the concept of durability and availability.
So durability represents how many times an object
is going to be lost by Amazon S three.
And so Amazon S three has a very high durability.
It's called 11 nines.
So nine nine point and then nine times nine percent.
And that means that on average,
if you store 10 million objects on Amazon S three,
you can expect to lose a single object
once every 10,000 years.
So it's quite durable.
And the durability is the same
for all storage classes in Amazon S three.
Availability represents how readily a service is.
And so this depends on the storage class.
For example, S three Standard has a 99.99% availability.
That means that about 53 minutes a year,
the service is not going to be available.
That means that you'll get some errors
when you deal with the service.
So you need to take that into account
when you develop your applications.
Okay.
So S3 standard has 99.99 availability.
It's going to be used for frequently accessed data.
This is the kind of storage you use by default,
and it has low latency and high throughputs.
It can sustain two concurrent facility failures
on the side of AWS and the use cases for it
is going to be big data analytics,
mobile and gaming application,
as well as content distribution.
Next, we have S three infrequent access.
So this is data that is going to be as the name indicates,
less frequently accessed,
but requires rapid access when needed.
It's going to be lower cost than S three Standard,
but you will have a cost on retrieval.
So the S three Standard-IA is 99.9% availability,
so a bit less available.
And the use case for it is going to be Disaster Recovery
and backups.
And Amazon S three One Zone-Infrequent access, One Zone-IA.
ESC has high durability, okay, within a single AZ only,
and the data is going to be lost
if the AZ is somewhat destroyed.
As well as durability, it's even lower.
So it's 99.5% availability.
And so the use cases of S three One Zone-IA
is to store secondary copy of backups
of maybe on-premises data, or data you can recreate.
Next we have the Glacier Storage Classes.
So Glacier is, as the name it gets very cold,
so it's low cost object storage
meant for archiving and backup.
And the pricing is that you're going to pay for the storage
plus pay for a retrieval cost.
In your three classes of storage within Glacier,
you have the Amazon S three Glacier Instant Retrieval.
And this gives you milliseconds retrieval
which is great for example,
for data that's accessed once a quarter,
and the minimum store duration is 90 days.
So this is backup,
but you need to access it within milliseconds.
Then we have the Glacier Flexible Retrieval.
It used to be called Amazon S three Glacier
but then they renamed things as they added more tier.
So the Amazon Glacier Flexible Retrieval
has three flexibility.
So you have expedited where you get the data back
between one and five minutes.
You have standard to get the data back
between three to five hours, or bulk, which is free,
where you get data back between five to 12 hours.
And the minimum storage duration as well is 90 days.
So here, instance means you retrieve data instantly
and flexible means that you're willing
to wait up to for example, 12 hours to retrieve your data.
And then we have Glacier Deep Archive
which is meant for long term storage.
So we have two tiers of retrieval as well.
We have Standard of 12 hours and Bulk of 48 hours.
So you may be ready to wait a lot of time
to retrieve data,
but it's going to give you the lowest cost,
and as well, the minimum storage duration is 180 days.
So as you know, that's a lot of storage classes
and there's one last called S three Intelligent- Tiering,
which is going to allow you to move objects
between excess tiers based on usage patterns.
And for this, you're going to incur a small
monthly monitoring fee, and auto tiering fee.
And there are no retrieval charges
in S three Intelligent- Tiering.
So there is the frequent access tier that's automatic
the default tier.
Then we have the Infrequent Access tier
for objects not accessed for example, for 30 days.
Then you have the Archive Instant Access tier,
automatic as well for objects not accessed over 90 days.
And then the Archive Access tier that's optional.
And you can configure it from 90 days to 700 plus days.
And then you have the Deep Archive Access tier
also optional, that you can configure for objects
that haven't been accessed between 180 days
to 700 plus days.
Okay.
So S three Intelligent-Tiering is really
to allow you to just sit back and relax
while S three moves objects for you.
So if you compare all the storage classes
you don't need to remember these numbers,
but it's just for you to make sense of what they are.
So you get durability of 11 nine's everywhere.
Then as availability goes down, the less zones you have,
of course.
It just shows you like for example
the minimum storage duration chart and so on.
So take some time to look at this diagram on your own.
You should understand it,
but you should not remember it for sure.
So if we look at some pricing, for example
in the us-east-one,
so this is the kind of pricing you would have
for all the storage classes.
And again, you're not supposed to remember everything.
But it's good for you to have a look at it
on your own time, just to make sure you understand.
Because if you understand what the classes name are,
then you should be able to make sense of these classes.
Okay?
So that's it for the lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.