So let's create a new bucket industry
and call it "s3-storage-classes-demos-2022."
Okay. Then I create into any kinda region,
and I will go ahead and just create this bucket.
So back in my bucket, I can go ahead
and upload a object, and click on add files.
I will choose my coffee.JPEG.
And let's have a look at the options.
So we can look at the properties
of that object,
and under storage class, I get the wide range
of storage class that are for AWS objects.
So we have S3 standard, okay,
and we get the design four column.
How many AZ's we have,
as well as some other (indistinct)
the minimum storage duration,
minimum billable object size,
and monitoring and auto-tiering fees.
So let's have a look at all of them.
So we have standard, which is the basic ones by default.
Then we get intelligent tiering,
in case we don't know our data patterns,
and therefore we want AWS
to perform the data tiering for us.
Standard-IA, if we want data to be infrequently accessed,
but still with low latency.
One-Zone-IA,
which is that you can recreate this data,
and it's going to be stored in one AZ only.
And therefore you can
run the risk of losing the object,
if the AZ is destroyed.
Then we have three glacier levels.
So we have Glacier Instant Retrieval,
Glacier Flexible Retrieval,
or a Glacier Deep Archive,
and it tells you exactly
what are the conditions in here.
And finally, Reduced Redundancy,
which is a deprecated type of storage tier,
and therefore I did not describe it in the course.
So what if we go with standard IA
for example, and create an object there.
So we're going there,
and then we're going to say upload.
Back in our bucket.
So now this object has the storage class, Standard-IA,
as it is shown here.
But what I can do is
that I can also change the storage class
if I wanted to.
So I can go into properties and scroll down,
and we can actually edit the storage class
to do something different.
So we can move it for example,
to One-Zone-IA,
in which case this object is going
to be stored in one zone only.
So let's save these changes.
And now my object has successfully been edited
and therefore the object class has changed.
So if we scroll down, now we are in One-Zone-IA.
And again, you could edit it,
and go, for example, for Glacier-Instant-Retrieval.
And now it's going to be archived,
or you can go for Intelligent-Tiering,
and it could be automatically set
to the right tier based on our patterns, and so on.
So you can see there's a lot of power using storage classes.
And finally,
I want to show you how we can automate moving these objects
between the different storage classes.
So let's go back
into our buckets, and there under management,
you can create lifecycle rules.
And you can create a rule,
and we'll call this one "DemoRule."
And then you're going to say,
"hey," apply to all objects in the buckets.
Yeah, sure.
And then we can say, okay
move current versions between storage classes.
And you're saying, hey, you go
to Standard-IA after, for example, 30 days.
And then you go to Intelligent-Tiering after 60 days.
And then you would go to Glacier-Flexible-Retrieval
after 180 days,
and so on.
So you get some transitions.
And in here you can review
all the transitions you have done.
So it is possible
for you to automate moving objects between tiers.
Okay. So that's it,
we've seen everything we need to know about storage classes.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.