So you might have one question
on S3 encryption at the exam,
so here is a high level review of what that means.
The first one is server-side encryption,
so it is by default whenever you create a bucket
or whenever you upload an object, it will be encrypted.
What is server-side encryption?
Well, the user uploads an object into Amazon S3,
and then that object when it arrives in the bucket
is going to be encrypted by Amazon S3 for security purposes.
The idea is that the server is doing the encryption,
and therefore we call this server-side encryption.
On the opposite, we have client-side encryption.
This is when the user will actually take the file,
will encrypt it before uploading it,
so the lock is done by the user,
and then put it in the bucket.
And that's called client-side encryption.
And both models exist in AWS,
but by default you should know
that server-side encryption is always on.
All right, that's it.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.