So, just a quick lecture
on IAM Access Analyzer for Amazon S3,
which is something that can come up
in the exam in one question.
So, what is this?
Well, this is a monitoring feature
for your Amazon S3 buckets to ensure
that only the intended people have access
to your S3 buckets.
So, how does that work?
Well, it's going to analyze your Bucket Policies,
your S3 ACLs, your S3 Access Point Policies,
and so on, and is going to surface to you
which buckets are going to be publicly accessible,
which buckets have been shared
with other AWS accounts and so on.
And the idea is that you can review this and say, okay,
this is normal, this is expected, or this looks a bit
as a security issue because I did not intend
to share this bucket with these people,
and therefore, you can take action.
And this is powered by IAM Access Analyzer,
which allows you to find out resources in your account
that are shared with other entities.
So, I hope that makes sense.
I hope you like this lecture
and I will see you in the next lecture.