As always, it's good to see
what is the shared responsibility model for Amazon S3.
So AWS is going to be responsible
for all the infrastructure.
That includes all the things specific to S3
so that their ability, availability,
the fact that it can actually sustain
current losses of two facilities.
As well as, I will see their own internal configuration
and vulnerability analysis.
And their own compliance validation
internally within their infrastructure.
And you as a user of Amazon S3,
you're supposed to set up correctly S3 Versioning
to make sure you set up the right S3 Bucket Policy
so that the data is protected within your buckets.
You need to make sure that if you want verification
you set it up yourself.
Logging and monitoring is optional
so you have to enable it yourself.
Making sure that you are using the most optimal
cost storage cloud that is going to be
the most cost friendly is also your responsibility.
And finally, if you wanted to encrypt your data
onto your Amazon S3 bucket,
that is up to you as well, okay?
So here we can really see what is the difference
between the responsibility of
AWS and yourself in this Amazon S3 service.
All right, that's it.
I will see you in the next lecture.