So now let's talk about the AWS Snow Family.
So this is a highly secure, portable device used
to collect and process data at the edge
and migrate data in and out of AWS.
So we have two kinds.
We have the Snowcone, it's a small device,
and we have the Snowball Edge, it's a much bigger device.
So each have their own specificity.
So the Snowcone is for very small storage capacity.
You have the option between 8 to 14 terabytes,
and usually you use the Snowcone when you have
a very small migration size of up to terabytes.
Snowball Edge is a much bigger device.
You have different flavors of it,
but the storage capacity can go, for example,
from 80 terabytes to 210 terabytes,
and you want to use them when you have
a migration size up to petabytes,
where you order many, many different Snowball Edge devices.
So why do we need Snowball devices in the first place?
Well, let's talk about data migrations.
So here is a table of how long it takes
to transfer 10 terabytes, or 100 terabytes, or 1 petabyte,
based on your connection speed.
So for example, if you want to transfer 100 terabytes
and you have a 1 gigabit per second connection,
then it would take you 12 days.
So obviously this would also take you
all your bandwidth from your company.
So when you have a limited connectivity or limited bandwidth
or your network costs can be very high,
or for example, you can't maximize the license
because you are sharing the bandwidth
or you have issues with connection stability,
then you want to use the AWS Snow Family,
because there are offline devices
and they allow you to perform data migrations.
So as a rule of thumb, if it takes you more than a week
to transfer data over the network,
then you should use Snowball devices.
So how does that work?
Well, this is a direct upload
from directly our client into Amazon S3,
but with the Snow Family, we order a Snowball
or a Snowcone device, it gets delivered to us,
then we load the data onto it, we ship it back to AWS,
and AWS is going to import it directly
into your Amazon S3 bucket.
So this is an offline data transfer.
So we first request a Snowball device
from the AWS console for delivery.
Then we install the Snowball clients
or something called AWS OpsHub
on their servers to transfer data.
Then we connect the Snowball device to our server
and we start copying files using the clients,
and then we ship back the device when we're ready.
It goes directly into an AWS facility.
The data is going to be loaded onto an Amazon S3 bucket,
and then your Snowball is completely wiped
and can be sent to another customer.
So this is for the data migration process,
but you also have edge computing.
So what is edge computing?
Well, this is to process data created on the edge location.
That means it could be a truck on the road
or a ship on the sea or a mining station on the ground.
And these locations they may have limited or no internet,
and they may have no access to computing power.
So here again, we order a Snowball Edge device
or a Snowcone device, and then we do edge computing.
Snowcone comes with a very, very simple CPU
and very low memory,
but it still can be helpful for some use cases.
And then on Snowball Edge,
you have this compute optimized instance,
which is dedicated for that use case,
which has a lot of processing power,
or the storage optimized also has some processing power.
And when you have a Snowball Edge, for example, device,
you can run EC2 instances or Lambda functions directly
on your Snowball Edge device directly at the edge.
So, the use cases for edge computing
is to pre-process data where it's created,
or to do machine learning, again on data where it's created
or to transcode media while it's being shipped back to AWS.
So let's see, we've seen Snowcone and Snowball Edge devices.
They're used for data migration and edge computing.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.