So let's have a look at the AWS
Snow Family Service.
So from the console you can actually order
a Snow family device and you have to name your job,
for example, demo job.
So we need to choose a job type, so we can import data
into Amazon S3, which is the most common use case.
We can also export data from Amazon S3.
You can order a Snow device just for local compute
and storage only.
This gives you some kind of device
that server that can runs in a remote place
without being connected to the internet.
Or you can import virtual tapes
into the AWS storage gateway.
So we'll choose the first option, import into Amazon S3
and here we have several options for Snow devices.
So we have Snowcone, Snowcone SSD,
Snowball Edge Storage Optimized with 80 terabytes.
And then we have the compute optimized
and the compute optimized with GPUs.
So it's possible that AWS will add options over time
and may not rerecord this video.
So, that's fine.
I always cover what's at the exam, so, don't worry.
And so, as you can see, we have several options
and we seen the previous lecture,
the use case for each option
so, I won't go over them.
But this is a nice way to know where you're getting.
Okay, so let's say we go, for example
with a compute optimized Snowball Edge.
Then we need to choose a pricing option.
So we have on demand pricing, monthly pricing
or then commitment for one or three year period.
Then we have the storage types.
So it's an S3 data transfer
and then what AMI do we want to use on it?
So, this is a compute type of instance.
So we can actually load an AMI for example
this Amazon Linux 2 first, no family,
but you could create your own AMI to have your own
compute needs.
Then where do you want to load the data onto?
So, what S3 buckets are available to you?
I have this one right here
but you can create your own S3 buckets.
Next, we have several features and options we can use.
So we have IoT Greengrass for Snow to have IoT capability
on your Snow device, but it's not needed.
And then we can do remote device management
by using OpsHub or the Snowball Clients.
So I'll click on next
then what type of encryption do we want
on our Snowball device.
So, we have this encryption key right here where
you can create your own KMS key and encrypt it with that.
Then you need to grant access of course to Amazon S3 and SNS
to publish actions and to send data.
So you need to create a service role.
And then you need to add an address
so where you want to ship it, which country, which states
and so on, as well as the shipping speed
and the SNS notification for your job status changes.
And then you'll get the job summary.
So that's it, you've seen all the options for Snow devices
and the Snow family.
Remember, it's most commonly used to send data
into Amazon S3 and out of Amazon S3.
And this gives you remote compute capabilities.
We've seen also the different kind of devices
which are Snowcone, Snowball, and Snowmobile.
All right, that's it.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.