Let's talk about Snowball Edge pricing.
So you're going to pay for usage of the device,
as well as data transfer out of AWS.
So if you take data from AWS onto your Snowball Edge
and then you receive it, then you're going to pay for this.
But instead, if you put data onto your Snowball Edge
and then put that data onto Amazon S3,
it's going to be free.
$0 per gigabytes.
So putting data in Amazon S3 is free.
Next, for the pricing of the device itself,
so there's two levels.
You have on-demand,
where you have a one-time service fee per job,
so you're going to pay something,
but as part of the service fee,
you're going to get 10 days of usage
for the 80 terabytes Snowball Edge Storage Optimized
or 15 days for the 210 terabytes.
And then the shipping days are not included
towards the 10 or 15 days limit.
So shipping from it was to you or from you to AWS is free.
And then just days of usage is counted
per days after 10 or 15 days.
Next, you have committed upfront
where you pay in advance for monthly, one year,
or three years usage of the Snowball Edge device.
This is to do edge computing.
And you get up to 62% of discounted pricing
because you are committing upfront to a long-term usage.
So that's it.
From an exam perspective,
I think we need to remember
is that everything you have to pay for,
except data into Amazon S3,
which costs you $0 per gigabytes.
Okay, that's it for this lecture, I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.