So now let's summarize
what we've learned about Amazon S3.
And I know that's a lot.
So first of all, we've learned
about the difference between Buckets and Objects.
So we know that Buckets must have a global unique name,
and is tied to a specific region
and Objects live within these Buckets.
For S3 security, we've seen that we can attach IAM policies
to users or to roles.
We've seen that we can also use S3 Bucket Policies.
For example, we granted public access
into an S3 Bucket, and we can set
up S3 Encryption to protect some files.
We can enable websites on an S3 bucket.
This is the idea to host a static website on Amazon S3.
You first need to make sure
that the Bucket, of course, is going to be public.
And then we can statically host some files.
We have S3 Versioning.
This is to have multiple versions for a file to prevent
against accidental deletes and to be able to roll
back to previous versions if we need to.
We've seen there are two kinds of S3 Replication.
You have the same-region replication
and the cross-region replication.
And for them to work, you must enable versioning beforehand.
We've seen different S3 storage classes.
We have standard, infrequent access,
one zone infrequent access, intelligent tiering
and we have three different classes for the Glacier
for (indistinct) purposes.
We've seen what the Snow Family is.
So there are physical devices that are used
to import data onto Amazon S3.
So you have like the Snowmobile, you have the Snowcone,
you have the Snowballs and so on.
And if you use a Snowcone or a Snowball edge device
then you can do edge computing on your data.
OpsHubs is a way to get a desktop application
to manage your Snow Family devices and add data onto them.
And finally, we've seen a way to extend on-premises storage
onto Amazon S3, that is using the AWS storage gateway.
So not so big lessons
but hopefully now you know all the specificity
of Amazon S3 that will allow you to answer all
the questions you need at the exam.
That's it.
I will see you in the next section.