Now let's talk about databases and AWS.
And first I want to give you an introduction
as to what is a database
and the different types of databases we have today.
So when you are storing data on disk,
would it be on an EBS drive, an EBS volume,
an EC2 Instance Store, Amazon S3, you have your limits.
If you want to store data in the structure way,
you may want to store it in a database.
And this structure is going to allow you
to build indexes and to efficiently query
or search through the data.
So well we have with EFS EBS, EC2 Instance Store
and Amazon S3, we can do per files operations
with databases, it's going to be a lot more structured.
We can even define relationships between your datasets.
So these databases nowadays,
they're all optimized for a purpose
and they will come with different features,
shapes and constraints.
From an exam perspective, it's up to you to understand
which database is going to fit best
at the use case given to you by the question.
So the first kind of database that has been very common
and it's still a very common today,
is called the relational databases.
So if you used Excel before, you know, Excel spreadsheets,
this is just the same as Excel spreadsheets,
but do you have links between each table.
So for example, we have the students table,
and as we can see, we have four columns
and there's a student ID, department ID,
a name and an email and then for example,
you would have a second spreadsheet
called the department spreadsheets
with text the department ID and as more information.
And the idea is that's in a relational database,
you are defining a relation between the department ID,
the second column in the students table,
into the first column of the departments table.
And you can even define more relations,
for example, you can define a subject's stable
and link the table of the students
to the subjects by defining another relation.
This is why it's called a relational database.
Now in relational databases,
the particularity clarity is that you can use
the SQL language to perform queries or lookups.
So these, whenever you hear SQL think relational databases.
Next, we have NoSQL Databases, NoSQL means non-SQL,
which means non relational databases.
So NoSQL are in more modern kind of databases.
They're built for a specific purpose
with a specific data model in mind
and have a flexible schema for building modern application.
The schema is basically the shape of the data.
So the benefits of using a NoSQL database
is that you have more flexibility.
It's easier to make the data model evolve,
it's scalable, so it's designed to scale out
by adding distributed servers.
So, the example from before the relational database,
it's not easy to add servers to scale it,
so you have to scale up by doing some vertical scaling,
but with no sequel databases, you can do horizontal scaling.
It's also high performance,
it's optimized for a specific data model.
It's highly functional,
the types are optimized for the model.
And finally, some examples of NoSQL databases
are going to be key-value databases,
document, graph, in-memory or a search databases.
We will be seeing those in this section.
So, for example, in the NoSQL database,
you can have the data in JSON format.
So JSON stands for JavaScript Object Notation,
and we've seen it before
this is the same language we've been using
when we defined our IAM policies,
and this is what a JSON document looked like.
As we can see, this does not look at all
like an Excel documents.
So JSON is a very common way to describe data
and as we can see in here,
we have different sub nesting of the data.
We have different fields, different name, different types.
And so, it is a very common way
to muddle data in a NoSQL model.
The data can be nested, for example,
if you look at address right here,
it is nested within the higher object elements.
So address and types are going to be nested.
The fields can change over time.
So it's up to us to add a new field into our JSON documents
and their support for arrays, for example,
John who is 30, has three different cars,
Ford, BMW, and Fiat, he's a lucky man.
Okay, so databases, as you can see get a different forms
and we'll be seeing them in details in the section.
So just some words around databases
and the shared responsibility model on AWS.
So AWS will offer to manage different databases for us.
So these are the offering we'll see
and the benefits of using a managed database,
is that it's very quick to provision.
Usually a database will have,
high availability in mind when designing it.
And if you wanna scale your database,
you can do vertical and horizontal scaling pretty easily.
They will also include some utilities
to do automated backup and restore of your databases
as well as operations and upgrades.
And if you need to patch the operating system
of the underlying instance,
actually it's not your responsibility anymore.
It's AWS's responsibility.
So AWS will be responsible for the entire database
in terms of patching.
The monitoring and alerting as well
are going to be integrated.
And so this is why using a managed database
on AWS is very, very important and very beneficial.
So, you are obviously able
to run your own database technology on an EC2 instance,
but if you do so, you need to handle yourself,
all the things associated with resiliency, backup, patching,
high availability, fault tolerance, and scaling.
So this is why in this case, using a managed database
is going to be a lifesaver
for so many of our use cases, okay?
So in this section,
we'll have a look at all the managed databases from AWS
and which use cases they fit.
So we'll see you in the next lecture.