The first kind of databases
we're going to see is the relational databases,
and for it we have RDS.
RDS stands for Relational Database Service,
so it's very clear that it's only for relational databases
and it will be using the SQL language.
So it's a managed database service for databases
that will use SQL as a query language,
and it will allow you to create databases
in the cloud that will be managed by AWS.
These databases can be of different kinds.
It could be a Postgres. MySQL, MariaDB.
Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server, IBM DB2,
and finally, something called Aurora,
which is a proprietary database from AWS,
which we'll be seeing in this lecture as well.
So why would we use RDS
instead of deploying our own databases on EC2?
Well, RDS is a managed database service,
so provisioning the database will be automatic.
The patching of the operating system will be done by AWS.
We will have continuous backups
and restore options with Point in Time Restore.
We'll have monitoring dashboards
to see if our database is doing good.
We'll be able to scale the reads by creating read replicas
and improve the read performance.
We will have the way to set up Multi AZ
to make sure that we're ready
to have a plan for disaster recovery
against a whole availability zone going down.
And finally, we can set up maintenance windows for upgrades
and we can scale vertically and horizontally.
This storage is going to be backed by EBS.
And the only thing that we cannot do
with an RDS database is that we cannot SSH
into your RDS database instance, okay?
We're just using the service,
AWS manage entirely the database for us,
so we cannot use the SSH utility
to see what's going on within our database.
Okay, so where does RDS fit
within our solution architecture?
Well, we have our load balancer,
and it's fronting multiple backend EC2 instances,
they're possibly into an auto scaling group,
and they need to store and share the data somewhere.
And this is structured data,
so they're not going to use EBS
or EFS or EC2 instance store,
they will be using a database and in this example,
it is a relational database, so SQL based.
And the EC2 instances will be connecting
to the database and doing read writes all at once.
So they will be sharing the database in the backend,
and this is a classic solution architecture,
not just using RDS, but using any kind of database.
You have the load balancer layer
that will be taking the web request,
the backend EC2 instances doing the application logic,
and the last tier, which is the right hand side,
which is going to be the database tier
doing the reads and the writes of the data.
Okay, so this is for RDS.
So now for Aurora.
So, Aurora is going to be a database technology
created by AWS, it's not open source,
and it works the same way as RDS.
We have our EC2 instances connecting directly
into Amazon Aurora.
And Aurora supports two kinds of database technologies.
It supports PostgreSQL and MySQL.
The idea with Aurora is that it's going
to be cloud optimized,
and so there is a 5x performance improvement
over MySQL on RDS and a 3x performance improvement
over using Postgres on RDS.
On top of things, we don't need to worry
about the storage of an Aurora database
because the storage will grow automatically
in increments of 10 gigabytes up to 128 terabytes.
Even if Aurora is going to be more expensive than RDS,
about 20% more, it's going to be more efficient,
and so it should be more cost effective.
Finally, Aurora is not something
that's included into the free tier of AWS, but RDS is, okay?
So from an exam perspective,
RDS and Aurora are going to be
the two ways for you to create relational databases on AWS.
They're both managed,
and Aurora is going to be more cloud native,
whereas RDS is going to be running the technologies
you know directly as a managed service.
And we also have a serverless option for Amazon Aurora.
So this is where the database
instantiation is going to be automated.
And on top of it, you will have auto-scaling
based on actual usage of your database.
So both PostgreSQL and MySQL are supported as engines
of Aurora Serverless Database.
You don't need to do any kind of capacity planning.
There's no management because you don't manage servers
and you're going to pay per second,
so it can be a lot more cost effective
than provisioning an Aurora cluster yourself.
So this is going to be great when you have infrequent
or intermittent or unpredictable workloads.
So how does that work?
Well, from the client perspective, it's super easy.
It connects to a proxy fleet that is managed by Aurora.
And Aurora, behind the scenes,
is going to instantiate database instances
when it needs to scale up or down.
And these Aurora databases are going
to be sharing the same storage volume no matter what.
So from an exam perspective,
if you see Aurora with no management overhead and so on,
think of Aurora Serverless.
Okay, so that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.