So when you deploy RDS databases, you need to understand
there are multiple architectural choices
you need to make, that you can make, actually.
So the first is to use RDS Read Replica.
So let's take the example of your application,
that reads from your main RDS database.
But say that now you need to scale the read workloads,
we have more and more applications
that need to read more and more data from RDS.
The way you can do it is by creating Read Replica.
So that means that there is gonna be some copies,
some replicas of your RDS database
that are going to be created.
And this is going to allow your applications
to read from this Read Replica also.
And therefore, you're distributing the reads
to many different RDS databases.
So you can create up to 15 Read Replicas.
So as you can see, in this example,
I have two Read Replicas on top of my main RDS database,
and my applications can read from all of them.
Now, when it comes to writing data,
writing data is only done to the main database,
so your application still have to write
to the only one central RDS database, okay.
So Read Replicas are used to scale reads.
Now we have Multi-AZ.
And so this is helpful when you have
to have failover in case of an AZ outage.
So in case in the availability zone,
like crashes, and this gives you high availability.
So in this example, your applications to read and write
from the same main RDS database, okay.
But we are going to set up
a replication cross AZ,
so in another different availability zone.
And this is going to be a failover database,
and this is why it's called Multi-AZ
because it's in a different AZ.
Now, in case the main RDS database crashes,
for whatever reason,
because maybe there's an issue with it,
or maybe because the AZ is having problems,
then RDS will trigger a failover.
And then your application will failover
to developer database in a different AZ.
So in this case, data is only read and written
to the main database.
The failover DB is passive,
it's not accessible until there is an issue
with the main database.
And you can only have one other AZ zone as a failover AZ.
The last kind of deployment you can do
is called Multi Region.
So this is for read replicas,
but this time, instead of being in the same region,
they are across different regions.
So to take an example,
we have EU-West one for RDS database,
and we're going to create a read replica in US-East two.
And so applications in US-East two can read locally
from this read replica.
But anytime this application needs to write data,
the writes need to happen across region.
And so we need to write the data to US one.
Same if you were to have also another region
in AP-Southeast two so in Australia,
you'd have the same concepts.
So why would you want a multi region type of deployments?
Well, number one,
because you want to set up a disaster recovery strategy,
in case of a region issue.
So if EU-West one is having a regional issue,
then you have a backup in either ES-East two,
or AP-Southeast two,
and this is why it's a disaster recovery strategy.
And also, as you can see,
our applications that are in different regions
get better performance, because they're read
from a local database, so they have less latency.
But finally, when you do this,
you need to understand that
because you are replicating data across regions,
then there is going to be a replication cost associated
with a network transfers of data between regions.
So that's it for RDS deployments,
the scenarios that will be proposed to you at the exam
will make it clear what department you choose.
So hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.