So now let's talk about a second type
of database you will see on AWS,
which is Amazon ElastiCache.
So the same way you use RDS to get
managed Relational Databases,
you're going to get ElastiCache to get a managed,
Redis or Memcached database.
These caches are going to be in-memory databases
with high performance, low latency.
So anytime in the exam you see something that says
you need an in-memory database,
you have to think directly ElastiCache.
Now ElastiCache will be helpful
to reduce load off of databases
that have a read intensive workloads.
The idea is that if we have an RDS database
and we're doing a lot of query on it
and they're the same queries all the time,
we put a bit of pressure onto that RDS database.
Instead what we could be doing,
is to use a cache to reduce the pressure
off of the database by making sure the queries
are directly going onto my in-memory database
through ElastiCache.
And because this is a managed database,
then AWS will take care of all the operating system
maintenance and patching, the optimizations,
the setup, the configuration, the monitoring,
failure recovery and backups.
So we've already learned a lot about caches in this exam
but we need to know it's an in-memory database
and the solution architecture around using a cache
looks like this.
So you're Elastic Load Balancer
will go to your EC2 Instances.
Possibly in an ASG.
They will be reading and writing data from
your Amazon RDS database, which is slow.
And then if possible there will be caching some values
into an Amazon ElastiCache database
and this will be very fast because it's in-memory.
And so with ElastiCache, there will be pressure
taken off the main RDS database
and put it on to the ElastiCache database
and that's the whole idea behind the cache.
You want to save the queries somewhere else,
so that they're very readily available.
Easily accessible and they can relieve, again pressure
from the main database.
So that's it, that's all you need to know going
into the exam and I will see you in the next lecture.