So now let's talk about DynamoDB.
DynamoDB is a fully managed, highly available database
with replication across three availability zone.
It is part of the NoSQL database family,
so it's not a relational database.
DynamoDB is one of the flagship product of AWS.
It scales to massive workload
and it's distributed serverless database,
that means that we don't provision any servers.
With RDS or with ElastiCache
we need to provision a instance type,
but with DynamoDB we don't.
So it's called a serverless database,
but there are still servers in the backend,
we just don't see them.
So DynamoDB is great
because it scales to millions of requests per seconds,
trillions of rows, and hundreds of terabytes of storage.
It has fast and consistent performance.
And so anytime you need a single digit millisecond latency
with low latency retrieval,
DynamoDB is the database for you.
So you would be looking for keywords in your exam,
such as serverless and low latency.
For example, single digit millisecond latency.
It is integrated with IAM for security,
authorization, and administration.
Has low cost and auto scaling capabilities.
And finally,
a standard and infrequent access, IA, table class
based on how you want to classify your data for cost saving.
So the question you may have is,
what type of data goes into DynamoDB?
Well, it's a key value database
and the data looks like this.
You have a primary key,
which is made of one or two columns,
a partition key and a sort key.
And then attributes on the right hand side
where you can define your own columns for your data.
Finally, all the items are going to be row by row.
And this is how a DynamoDB table works.
Very, very simple,
but again, remember it's a NoSQL database.
It has low latency retrieval of data
and you also get access to a serverless database.
Then we have DynamoDB Accelerator also called DAX.
In the exam both can be used.
So it is a fully managed in-memory cache for DynamoDB.
So this is a cache that's specific for DynamoDB
so it's not like ElastiCache.
So for example, say your application wants
to access DynamoDB tables in DynamoDB,
for this if you want to cache
the most frequently read objects,
then you would use DAX or DynamoDB Accelerator
as a cache in between.
And DAX is made just for DynamoDB. Okay?
So you would not use ElastiCache in this case.
Even though you could, you would use DAX
because it's already really, really well integrated
with DynamoDB.
So this is going to give you a 10x performance improvement.
So instead of digit,
instead of single digit millisecond latency to read records,
you will have microseconds latency
when accessing your DynamoDB tables.
It's going to be fully secure, highly scalable,
and highly available.
And the difference with ElastiCache again,
is that DAX is only used in,
it's fully integrated with DynamoDB.
Whereas ElastiCache can be used for other types of databases
to provide caching capabilities.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it
and I will see you in the next lecture.