Okay, so let's go ahead and practice
DynamoDB a little bit.
So I'm going to create a table,
and I'll call this one DemoTable.
Now in DynamoDB what you need to do
is specify a partition key, so specify user_id,
and sort keys are definitely out of scope for the exam,
so let's just consider just the partition key.
Okay, so, now for the settings in DynamoDB, again,
I'm going to leave it as a default settings,
you don't need to know the details of how it works,
and then you scroll down and you click on Create table.
So our table is now creating,
and what I'm going to notice is that we are creating
a table without creating a database.
So the database already exists, it's serverless,
we don't need to provision servers.
We just want you to say,
"Hey, look, I want this table, please create it for me
and I don't care how it's being run."
And that's the whole power of DynamoDB,
that's the whole power of serverless services.
So now that the table is ready
we can click on View items, and practice a little bit
inserting some data into this table.
So currently zero items are returned
because I haven't created anything,
but we can create an item in DynamoDB.
And for user_id I can say 1234,
so that will be my user ID.
We can have a first name to be equal to Stephane,
and we can have a last name to be equal to Maarek,
and then, finally, we could have a number.
So I can see lot of different types we can have, by number,
and it could be my favorite number, and it's 42,
and click on Create item.
And here we go, my item was written into DynamoDB.
So this is super easy, yet, again,
I do not have to specify any database, just my table,
write some item, and so on.
And we didn't have to specify this schema,
it just get automatically inferred,
now we have four attributes or columns.
Now if I can create a second item, so 45678,
and then add a new string, so, for example, first_name.
In here we're going to have Alice, and click on Create item.
So, as we can see, in this example,
I didn't specify a favorite number or last name for Alice,
I just specified first name Alice,
and it was still accepted by DynamoDB.
So it's a very flexible type of database,
it's a very flexible way to insert data,
and this whole, like, test sets of features
and particularities make DynamoDB really, really good.
But the difference between DynamoDB and, say, RDS
is that DynamoDB will have all the data
living within one single table,
and there's no way to join it with another table.
So it's not a relational database,
that's when DynamoDB is a non SQL database,
so not only SQL database, so NoSQL.
And the idea, here, is that, yes,
we cannot link this table to another table,
so we need to make sure that all the relevant data
is well formatted within our main DynamoDB table.
So it changes a little bit
how you see database designs and so on.
But that's it for DynamoDB, a very quick hands-on
to show you an overview, but with DynamoDB
it's a lot more to learn and this is the focus
of the Certified Developer exam,
not the Cloud Practitioner exam.
So, for this example, this is enough,
and when you're done and ready
you can just delete the table.
You can delete all the CloudWatch alarms
associated with it, and just type delete in this box
and you'll be good to go.
So that's it for this lecture, I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.