Okay, so now let's talk about
DynamoDB global tables.
So this is a one feature need to know about for DynamoDB.
It's a way for you to make DynamoDB table
accessible with low latency and this is the key
in multiple regions.
So let's take an example.
We have our DynamoDB table in us-east-one,
and we'll set up as a global table.
So the basics, of course, our users can do read and write
to this DynamoDB table in Northern Virginia us-east-one.
But it is possible for us
to set up some replication for this global table.
So we can create a global table in Paris eu-west-three
and we'll say they're the same,
so there's two way replication between these tables.
That means that the same data is in us-east-one
and in eu-west-three,
but users, you know, there are close to the Paris region,
can access this global table with low latency in Paris.
So this is true for one to 10 regions, if you want it to.
Okay.
A global table is truly global
and users can read and write
to the table in any specific region,
there will just be replication between these two.
So the fact that there is read/write access
to any region of AWS on this global table,
makes it an active-active replication
because you can actively write to any region
and it will actively be replicated into other regions. Okay.
So that's it, all you need to know for the exam.
I will see you in the next session.