Okay, next type of database we have
is Redshift.
Redshift is a database
that is based on PostgreSQL,
but it's not used for OLTP.
OLTP stands for Online Transaction Processing.
That is what RDS was good for.
Instead, Redshift is OLAP,
or Online Analytic Analytical Processing,
which is used to do analytics and data warehousing.
So anytime in the exam you're saying a database
needs to be a warehouse and to do analytics on it,
then Redshift is going to be your answer.
With Redshift, you don't load the data continuously.
You load it, for example, every hour.
And the idea with Redshift that is really,
really good at analyzing data and making some computations.
So it boasts 10x better performance
than other data warehouses and scales to petabytes of data.
The data is stored in columns,
so it's called a columnar storage
of data instead of row-based.
So anytime you see columnar, again,
think Redshift, and it has something called
the Massively Parallel Query Execution MPP engine
to do these computations very, very quickly.
It's pay as you go based
on the instances you have provisioned,
and has a SQL interface to perform the queries.
It's also finally integrated with BI,
so business intelligence tools such as QuickSight or Tableau
if you wanted to create dashboards on top of your data
in your data warehouse.
So that's it.
Just a high level overview, but a data warehouse is used
to do some computation on your data sets
and do some analytics,
and possibly build some kind of visualizations
through dashboards on it.
And so for that use case, Redshift
would be perfect.
We now have a feature
for Redshift called Redshift Serverless,
and this allows you to run Redshift but not worry
about scaling the data warehouse or provisioning it.
(indistinct) does it for us,
that's what it's called, serverless.
So the idea is that you're going
to run your analytics workloads
without managing data warehouse infrastructure,
which is very handy, and you're only going to pay
for what you use, which allows you to save on costs.
So the use cases will be to do reporting
or dashboarding applications, or realtime analytics,
but again, without managing the underlying capacity
and the infrastructure
of your Redshift Serverless database.
So how does that work?
Well, you just enable Amazon Redshift Serverless
on your account.
Then you connect the Redshift Query Editor
or any other tool to start writing your queries,
and then automatically Redshift Serverless is going
to run these queries and provision and scale capacity based
on the workload and the query itself.
Finally, you only pay for compute
and storage used during the analysis,
which makes it a very cost efficient option
to running Redshift,
and the exam can test you on it as well.
Okay, so that's it for this lecture.
I hope you liked it and I will see you in the next lecture.