Another type of database we have
on AWS is Amazon EMR, and EMR stands for Elastic MapReduce.
So EMR is actually not really a database.
It's to create what's called a Hadoop cluster
when you wanna do big data on AWS,
and a Hadoop cluster is used to analyze
and process vast amount of data.
So Hadoop is an open source technology,
and they allow multiple servers that work in a cluster
to analyze the data together, and so when you're using EMR,
you can create a cluster made of hundreds of EC2 instances
that will be collaborating together to analyze your data.
So part of the Hadoop ecosystem, the Big Data ecosystem,
you will see projects names such as Apache Spark, HBase,
Presto, and Flink, and all these things
will be working on top of your Hadoop cluster.
So what is EMR then?
Well, EMR takes care of provisioning all these EC2 instances
and configuring them so that they work together
and can analyze together data from a big data perspective.
Finally, it has auto-scaling
and it is integrated with Spot instances,
and the use cases for EMR will be data processing,
machine learning, web indexing, or big data in general.
So from an exam perspective,
any time you see Hadoop cluster,
think no more, it's going to be Amazon EMR.
That's it, I hope that was helpful,
and I will see you in the next lecture.