So now let's talk about Amazon Athena.
Amazon Athena is a serverless query service
to perform analytics against your objects
stored in Amazon S3.
So the idea is that you would use the SQL query language to
create these files, but you don't need to load them.
They just need to be in S3 and Athena will do the rest.
So these files can be formatted in different ways,
such as CSV, JSON, ORC, Avro, and Parquet
and the Athena is built on the Presto engine,
if you must know.
Now, how does it work?
So users will load it into Amazon S3,
and then Amazon Athena will be used
to query and analyze the data.
Very, very simple.
And then if you wanted to,
you could have some reporting on top of Athena,
such as using Amazon QuickSight.
Now the pricing for Athena is around
$5 per terabyte of data scanned.
And if you use compressed
or data stored in a columnar fashion,
then you're going to have cost savings
because there is less scan of the data being made.
So the use cases of Athena are multiple,
but anytime you see Business intelligence,
analytics, or reporting,
or to analyze Flow Logs in VPC or ELB Logs,
or CloudTrail logs, or platform logs,
all these kinds of logs in AWS,
then Athena's going to be a really, really good option.
So from an exam perspective,
whenever you see serverless analyze data in S3
use SQL, then think Amazon Athena.
That's it.
I hope you liked it.
And I will see you in the next lecture.