Now let's talk about Amazon QuickSight.
So it's a serverless, machine learning-powered
business intelligence service
to create interactive dashboards.
So behind this very complicated tagline,
all you have to remember is that Amazon QuickSight
allows you to create dashboards on your databases
so we can visually represent your data
and show your business users
the insights they're looking for, okay.
So QuickSight allows you to create
all these kind of cool graphs, charts, and so on.
So it's fast, it's automatically scalable.
It's embeddable and there's per-session pricing,
so you don't have to provision any servers.
The use cases are business analytics,
building visualizations, performing ad-hoc analysis,
get business insights using data.
And in terms of integrations, there are so many,
but, for example, QuickSight can run on top
of your RDS database, it can run on top of Aurora,
Athena, Redshift, Amazon S3, and so on.
So QuickSight is your go-to tool for DI in AWS.
That's it. I will see you in the next lecture.