So now let's talk about Amazon Timestream.
And, as there's a hint in the name, it is for time series.
So it's a database that is fully managed, fast, scalable,
and serverless for time series data.
So what is time series data?
Well, it's data that is evolving over time.
So, for example, here on the vertical axis we have a number,
and on the horizontal axis we have the year
that is evolving from an older date to a newer date.
And so because the date is evolving over time,
we are talking about a time series datasets.
So Timestream is just for that,
and there's automatic scaling up and down
based on capacity and the need of computes.
You can store and analyze trillions
of events per day in time series form.
It's about a thousand times faster
and one 1/10th of the cost of relational databases.
On top of it, if you want to analyze
the time series data in real time,
you could have time series analytics function
to find your pattern in your database.
So, whenever at the exam you see time series data,
think no more than Amazon Timestream.
All right, that's it.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.