Now let's talk about,
Amazon Managed Blockchain.
So what is Blockchain?
It makes it possible to build applications
where multiple parties can execute transactions
without the need for trusted central authority.
So there's a decentralization aspect to a Blockchain.
So managed Blockchain by Amazon,
is a service to join a public Blockchain networks
or create your own scalable private
Blockchain network within AWS.
And it's compatible with two Blockchain so far,
the framework Hyperledger Fabric,
and the framework Ethereum.
So from an exam perspective,
if you see anything related to Blockchains
or Hyperledger fabric or Ethereum,
you have to think Amazon managed Blockchain
which is also a decentralized Blockchain, okay?
So make sure you remember that and that's it,
all you want to know for the exam,
you'll need to be Blockchain experts.
So that's it, I hope you liked it,
and I will see you in the next lecture.