Okay, now let's talk about AWS Glue.
So, Glue is a managed extract, transform, and load service,
or ETL, and from an exams perspective,
that's all you need to know.
But let's go a little bit deeper dive,
to understand how that works.
So, what is ETL?
Well, ETL is very helpful when you have some datasets
but they're not exactly in the right form,
or the right format that you need,
to do your analytics on them.
And so the idea is that you would use an ETL service
to prepare and transform that data.
So, Glue does that, but traditionally you use servers
to do it, but with Glue it's a fully serverless service,
so you just worry about the actual data transformation,
and Glue does the rest.
So, in a diagram for example, Glue ETL sits in the middle,
and say we wanted to extract data from both an S3 Bucket
and an Amazon RDS database.
So, for this, we'd use Glue to extract the data
from both these sources, and then,
once the data is extracted, it is in a Glue service,
and we would write a script to do a transform part.
So here, Glue would help us transform the data,
and then, once it's transformed,
we need to actually analyze it so we can load up that data
into, for example, an Amazon Redshift database,
where we can do our analytics the right way.
And so, Glue sits here, okay?
It's a very powerful tool, because you can do any kind
of instruction transformation
and then you can load it into many different places.
So, that's for Glue ETL, and then there's another service
called Glue Data Catalog, which I think is not at the exam,
but I will still mention it to you 'cause it's important
to know it as part of the Glue family.
So, the Glue Data Catalog, as the name indicates,
is a catalog of your datasets in your Alias infrastructure,
and so this Glue Data Catalog will have a alert reference
of everything, the column names, the field names,
the field types, et cetera, et cetera.
And this can be used by services such as Athena,
Redshift and EMR to discover the datasets
and build the proper schemas for them, okay?
So, that's it. I hope you liked this lecture,
and I will see you in the next lecture.