So we have seen in this section
so many different database technologies
and the question is how do you migrate data
from one database to another?
For this we can use DMS which is properly named
the Database Migration Service.
So we use source database and once we extract the data
so we'll run an EC2 instance
that will be running the DMS software.
We'll extract the data from the source database
and then DMS will insert the data back
into a target database that will be somewhere else.
So with DMS we get a quick and secure database migration
into AWS that's going to be resilient and self healing.
And the cherry on the cake,
the source database remains available during the migration
so we don't have to take it down.
It supports many kinds of migration.
So one it's called an homogeneous migration
where you have Oracle to Oracle for example.
So it's the same database technology for the source database
and the target database.
Or it supports heterogeneous migrations
when the source database technology
and the target are different for example
a Microsoft SQL Server to Aurora.
And in that case, DMS is smart enough
to know how to convert data
from the source into the target.
So any time in the exam you see migration of a database,
DMS is going to be the answer for it.
I hope that was helpful
and I will see you in the next lecture.